mbed.com 2017-09-24

# Policies | Privacy Policy – ARM

## What does this policy cover?

This policy explains how We are committed to safeguarding the privacy of users of websites operated by, or on behalf, of ARM Limited (together “ARM Websites”). 

This statement explains how We collect, use and safeguard Data (defined below) you provide when using an ARM Website. Any personal information which may be collected from an ARM Website will be treated in accordance with this privacy policy, the Data Protection Act 1998, as amended and other applicable laws. For the purposes of the Data Protection Act 1998, where ARM is the data controller, the data controller is ARM Limited, a company registered in England and Wales with company number 2557590 (“We/Us/Our”). Registered office address: 110 Fulbourn Road, Cambridge CB1 9NJ, United Kingdom. ARM Limited is a private limited company acting on behalf of itself and its subsidiaries.

This privacy policy incorporates the following additional terms and conditions and policies:

  * Terms and Conditions of Use
  * Cookie Policy

By using an ARM Website, you consent to the collection and use of your information in the manner and for the purposes set out below.

  * What information do We collect
  * Where We store your Data
  * Other Data Collectors
  * How We use your Data
  * Specific ARM Websites or Product Practices
  * Disclosure of your Data
  * Your rights
  * Security of your Data
  * Retention of your Data
  * Changes to this privacy policy

## What information do We collect?

**Information provided by you** : When you send Us an email or visit an ARM Website, We may collect, from both public and private areas of the ARM Website, personal information volunteered by you about you, including but not limited to your name, title, company, county, mailing address, email address, phone numbers, fax numbers, age range and company size, design areas, and content which you upload and create in both public and private areas of the Website, including but not limited to source code, object code and documentation. This information also includes any information that you provide by filling in forms on the Website, registering to use the Website or subscribing to or using any service through the Website, uploading material or requesting further services. We may also ask you for information when you report a problem with our Website and may record correspondence when you contact us. 

**Information collected by Us** : Our web server logs, browser cookies and local shared objects may collect details of your domain name, operating system, browser type, IP address, a unique identifier for your computer, or other access device and details of your visits to the Website including, but not limited to, traffic data, location data, weblogs and other communication data, the services and resources that you access and your use of such resources.

We refer to both of the above types ofinformation collectively as “Data”. When you submit Data you are agreeing to its transfer, storage and processing by or on behalf of ARM.

**Cookies**

We collect and store information about your visit to Our Website automatically using browser cookies (files which are sent by Us to your computer) or similar technology which We can access when you visit Our Website in future. To read more about cookies and local shared objects please visit our Cookie Policy.

## Where We store your Data?

When you are on an ARM Website and are asked for Data, you are sharing that Data with ARM Limited, its subsidiaries and related companies. The Data may be stored on ARM servers in the European Economic Area (“EEA”) or transferred to and stored at a destination outside the EEA. Data may be disclosed to and processed by staff operating outside of the EEA who work for Us, Our subsidiaries, Our related companies, and companies who We have contracted to process or store Data on Our behalf. Please note that privacy laws in countries outside of the EEA may not be the same as, and in some cases may be less protective than, the privacy laws in your country, and while in the country outside of the EEA Personal Data may be subject to lawful access requests by government agencies.

We take what we believe to be reasonable steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your Data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Unfortunately the transmission of information via the internet, server, database, network or email transmission is never fully secure or error free. Although we will do our best to protect your Data, we cannot guarantee the security of your Data transmitted to the Website, any transmission is at your own risk and please keep this in mind when disclosing any Data. Once we have received your Data, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access. 

When we transfer your Data to servers controlled by a third party data hosting company either within the EEA or operating outside of the EEA, we conduct security checks on these companies to ensure adequate safeguards are in place to protect the transfer of your Data.

**Other Data Collectors**

The ARM Website may also contain various links to third-party web sites. Third-party web sites may provide additional information, goods, services and/or promotions. These sites are owned and operated independently from Us, and have their own separate privacy and data collection practices. Any Data you provide to these websites will be governed under the terms of their privacy policy, if any. We have no responsibility or liability whatsoever for the independent actions or policies of these independent sites, and are not responsible for the content or privacy practices of such sites. 

## How We use your Data?

We use your Data in the following ways:

  * to contact you with requested information. If you provide Personal Data for a certain purpose, we may use the Personal Data in connection with the purpose for which it was provided;
  * provide further information in respect of any products downloaded or purchased from Us; 
  * provide information in respect of Our events;
  * to send marketing information and to display content and advertising on or of services or products the same or similar products or services to those you have purchased or downloaded from Us, Our Subsidiaries and Our related companies that We believe might be of interest to you; and
  * in order to allow access to or use of the services you have purchased or downloaded from Us, Our Subsidiaries and Our related companies (“Services”) or any functionality thereof, we will use your Personal Data to provide you with access to or use of the Services or functionality and to monitor your use of such Services or functionality.

We also use your Data to:

  * update Our databases; 
  * maintain a technical support history;
  * determine trends in your use of Our products; which then aids in the design of new products and services;
  * process your enquiries; 
  * measure the use of Our sites; 
  * display materials on the appropriate ARM Website where you have uploaded materials for that purpose; 
  * for internal business purposes, including without limitation, to help us improve the content and functionality of the Services, to better understand our Users, to improve the Services, to protect against, identify or address wrongdoing, to enforce our Terms of Service/ Use, to manage your account and provide you with customer service, and to generally manage the Services and our business;
  * to analyse materials you have uploaded and created for our own purposes and to collect and analyse information on how the Website is being used (in accordance with the appropriate terms and conditions);
  * to research and develop new services; and 
  * administer and improve the content of Our sites and services.

**Responsive Communication / Support**

We will often use your Personal Data to respond to your requests, for example, if you email our customer support department we will return your email to respond to your query. Notwithstanding any unsubscribe election that you have made in respect of receiving marketing emails, you will still receive these emails since these are non-marketing emails. You can stop receiving these types of emails by requesting support email notifications are stopped. We do not recommend that you do this unless you plan to no longer use the relevant products or services, are not currently using our products or services / ARM Websites and will have no need to receive further communications from us or through our system. 

**ARM Events**

We will use your Personal Data in order to administer any ARM events your register to attend, and may need to pass your Personal Data to Our event partners for the purposes of effectively running such events. For example, Our event partners may use your Personal Data to help organise the event or help Us register attendees at the event, schedule meetings at the event and administrate an application for the event.

**Social Media**

If you connect or integrate any social media services with services we provide, you may receive social notifications either from us or from third party companies providing social media services. You can manage these social notifications through changing your privacy settings on the relevant social media site or discontinuing any interaction with this third party site. If you register and provide information to a forum or blog, the information you provide will be published for anyone to see or where you create a connection between ARM services and third party sites, we may collect, use, disclose, transfer and store/retain information relating to your account with such third party services in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

**Recruitment / Careers site**

We collect information when you submit online applications for the jobs advertised on our ARM Websites. We will use your Personal Data to process your application and may pass your information to third parties to conduct further screening of your Personal Data and to process the application you submit. We will not process your information further except in accordance with the recruitment process.

**Children**

If you are under the age of eighteen (18), please do not submit any Personal Data through the services/ ARM Websites. We do not knowingly collect Personal Data from children under the age of eighteen (18). We encourage parents and legal guardians to monitor their children’s internet usage and to not allow children to ever provide Personal Data through the Services without their permission. 

**Specific Uses of Your Data on Specific ARM Websites / Specific Product Practices**

The following notices explain specific privacy practices with respect to certain ARM products or services that you may use on ARM Websites:

**Developer.arm.com**

If you request information regarding ARM’s Development Tools We may share your Data with Our approved distributors who cover distribution of ARM’s Development Tools in your country and they will supply you with the requested information. We partner with other embedded tool companies and semi-conductor manufacturers to provide you with important or interesting information about products or services that you may find beneficial. We may provide your Data to these third parties to enable them to provide you with such information. 

**mbed.com, mbed.org, mbedcloud.com (together “mbed Websites”)**

**Internet Of Things Business Unit**

**Your accounts on mbed Websites:**

In order to use some services offered on mbed Websites you may be asked to register an account or provide an existing ARM Account via the mbed Website. In order to register an account you may be asked to input certain fields of Data. This Data will be used in accordance with your registered account and in accordance with this Privacy Policy more generally. 

During your use of mbed services, and during any subsequent changes, updates or attempts to resolve issues you bring to our attention we may access, and collect technical information from or about your use of the services including information about devices used in connection with mbed services and related device data. We may use this information for changes to the services or security or maintenance associated with the mbed Account you use for mbed services. 

**What information do We collect:**

When using services offered on mbed Website you or End Users of yours may create or collect information or Data through the use of an mbed enabled device or through use of ARM’s mbed service. In the course of providing these services, ARM automatically collects and receives encrypted non-personally identifiable and potentially personally identifiable information from mbed enabled devices. 

**Where do We store your Data:**

We may store this Data and transfer this Data to an external third party hosting company. The Data may be stored in the European Economic Area (“EEA”) or transferred to and stored at a destination outside the EEA. Data may be disclosed to and processed by staff operating outside of the EEA who work for Us, Our subsidiaries, Our related companies, and companies who We have contracted to process or store Data on Our behalf. Please note that privacy laws in countries outside of the EEA may not be the same as, and in some cases may be less protective than, the privacy laws in your country, and while in the country outside of the EEA Personal Data may be subject to lawful access requests by government agencies.

**How We use your Data/Disclosure of your Data:**

You consent to our collection, use, disclosure, transfer and storage, of your Data associated with the services and you understand and acknowledge that our Privacy Policy applies only to the services we provide to you and not to End Users Data. We may disclose your Data to third parties in order to assist in providing the services. The Data may be used by us or third parties for the purposes of improving user experience. 

You acknowledge that we are a data processor only in respect of the services offered and you are a data controller in respect of the Data submitted by you and your End Users’ as part of the services. You are fully responsible for putting in place adequate levels of protection for End Users’ Data to comply with all relevant applicable data protection laws, principles and agreements globally. This Privacy Policy does not apply to your use of End Users’ Data. Data provided by End Users should be subject to different and additional terms. You are required to enter into agreements directly with end Users to include provisions in relation to but not limited to management of the collection, use, disclosure, transfer of your End Users’ Data including ensuring that sufficient technical and organizational measures are in place to safeguard Data. To the extent to which we require rights from End Users’ to process Data as requested by you or your End Users, you are fully responsible for obtaining those rights prior to providing Data to us. 

**Keil.com**

**Keil**

If you request information regarding products on the Keil pages of the ARM Website We may share your Data with Our approved distributor in your country and the will supply you with the requested information. We partner with other embedded tools companies and semi-conductor manufacturers to provide you with important or interesting information about products or services that you may find beneficial. We may provide your Data to these third parties to enable them to provide you with such information. 

If you purchase a licence for a KEIL software tool, in order to register such licence for activation you will be asked to provide us with certain personal information including your name, email address and organisation. We may share this information with individuals employed by your organisation who have registered KEIL software licences with us using the same domain name as you, solely for the purposes of monitoring and administering licence registrations and assisting your organisation in complying with licensing mechanisms. 

If you wish to update or change any information We hold about you regarding the Keil pages of the ARM Website you may complete Our Keil customer information maintenance form [https://www.keil.com/product/custserv.asp]. 

If you wish to remove your email address from Our Keil product update mailing list, you may do so here [http://www.keil.com/update/udremove.asp].

**ARM University Program**

**What information do We collect:**

We will collect the information provided by you when contacting Us, taking part in an online survey, giveaway or other competition, and/or subscribing to Our newsletter. The information We collect may include (without limitation) your name, email address, occupation, employment details, institution details, and residential address.

**How We use your Data/Disclosure of your Data:**

We will use the personal information that you have provided to Us:

  * to contact you to provide you with information, products or services that you may have requested;
  * to provide you with marketing information in relation to the same or similar products or services that you have already requested from Us;
  * to provide you with other marketing information, where you have indicated that you wish to receive such information; 
  * to conduct market research; and
  * to inform the development of Our future programs, products and services.

**ARM Education Media**

**What information do We collect:**

We may collect information and statistics that enable you to be identified, for example, information about your browser, your operating system and settings, the referrer URL (that is your last visited website) and IP address. The information collected may also include information relating to your behavior and navigation on the website. 

If you purchase access to Our products via the ARM Education Media website, register on the ARM Education Media website to use one of Our products, or request access as a course administrator, We may ask for your name, email address, postal address, and other relevant personal information. Personal information submitted in this way is added to Our access control database, hosted by a third party hosting company and it may also be added to Our in-house customer databases. This information will be updated if you inform Us of any changes.

We request personal information (such as your name, email address and other contact details) from you when you contact Us with any account management queries, technical problems, to comment on the ARM Education Media website, or when you ask for information about Our products and/or services. 

We will collect data from surveys completed by you but completion of these surveys is not compulsory. If you are registered to take a course in your individual capacity, you may be asked to complete survey questions on your learning experience and capability self-assessment. If you are registered to take a course via an institution, you may be asked to complete survey questions (either during or on completion of the course) on the climate at your institution, your learning experiences and capability self-assessments. 

**How We use your Data/Disclosure of your Data:**

We will use your personal information to enable Us to verify that you are registered to take a course and to provide you with access to restricted areas of the ARM Education Media website for the purposes of completing Our course(s).

We may track information on your progress through the course and on whether you have met the requirements for successful training by asking you to complete a quiz at the end of the course. We may share this information with your institution and We may also use it in an anonymized form to generate usage statistics. 

We may use your information to carry out Our obligations arising from the agreement between Us and the institution with which you are registered (for example, disclosing to the course administrator at your institute the outcome of the quiz you take at the end of the course). 

If you register with Us, you will receive ARM Education Media newsletters, via the email address you have provided. You will have an option to unsubscribe from these newsletters at any time. 

Personal information submitted by you via the “contact us” page on the ARM Education Media website will not be added to Our customer databases and We request it simply so that We can respond to you about your query. Statistics regarding the types of queries submitted to Us via the “contact us” page may be collated by Us in aggregate form so that We can effectively monitor the website and improve levels of service.

If you are registered to take a course in your individual capacity and you choose to respond to surveys, data will be gathered, processed and used anonymously to improve our products and levels of service. 

If you are registered to take a course via an institution and you choose to answer surveys, data will be gathered from your responses and passed back to your institution in a way that does not allow your institution to identify you, to assist your institution to assess the effectiveness of their training schemes. You should note that certain survey questions may allow for open/free text responses. We do not review, edit or moderate such responses before submission to your institute so do not identify yourself expressly or by including comments which would allow your institution to be able to identify you. We do not accept any responsibility or liability if you are identified as a result of comments you have made in a survey. If We believe that the information you submit is unlawful or potentially damaging to others, We reserve the right to disclose your identity to third parties to the extent that it is reasonably necessary in Our opinion to prevent, remedy or take action in relation to such conduct. In addition to sharing your anonymized survey data with your institution, this data may be aggregated with data from other institutions participating in the same courses and used as benchmark data for institutional comparison purposes; and to assist Us to review, develop and improve Our services. 

We may combine all information which We collect about you (excluding any information We collect about you through Our surveys) so that We can better understand, and in turn, provide you and other customers with more customised and better information, products and services, viewing recommendations and advertising.

We share your information within ARM. We also share your information with Our licensors and suppliers, which assist Us in making Our products and services (e.g. our hosting supplier).

The ARM Education Media website contains various links to third-party web sites. These sites are not within Our control and are not covered by this privacy policy. They are owned and operated independently from Us, and have their own separate privacy and data collection practices. Any Data you provide to these websites will be governed under the terms of their privacy policy, if any. Please check those policies before you submit any personal data to such third party websites. We have no responsibility or liability whatsoever for the independent actions or policies of these independent sites, and are not responsible for the content or privacy practices of such sites. 

**ARM Community**

**Your ARM Community account:**

In order to use ARM Community site offered on community.arm.com you are asked to register an account or provide your existing ARM Community Account details via community.arm.com. 

**What information do We collect:**

In order to register an account you may be asked to input certain fields of Data including your email address, display names, user names, a profile picture and any profile information you choose to contribute to the ARM Community site which may include your job title, your phone number, your expertise, your company, your biography, your location, your interests, any social media links you may have, a link to a blog or a website you may have. You may also choose to include your fields of interest, your profession and the length of your experience in that profession. This Data will be used in accordance with your registered account and in accordance with this Privacy Policy more generally. 

You may contribute content through the use of the ARM Community site which may be considered Data since you can be identified by this Data. ARM’s use of your Data will be in accordance with this Privacy Policy and ARM’s use of any non-personally identifiable data / content you contribute will be in accordance with the ARM Community Terms and Conditions/ Terms of Use. 

**Where do We store your Data:**

We may store this Data and transfer this Data to an external third party hosting company. The Data may be stored in the European Economic Area (“EEA”) or transferred to and stored at a destination outside the EEA. Data may be disclosed to and processed by staff operating outside of the EEA who work for Us, Our subsidiaries, Our related companies, and companies who We have contracted to process or store Data on Our behalf. Please note that privacy laws in countries outside of the EEA may not be the same as, and in some cases may be less protective than, the privacy laws in your country, and while in the country outside of the EEA Data may be subject to lawful access requests by government agencies, however, we will endeavour to ensure that the country / third party that your Data is transferred to has adequate safeguards in place. 

**How We use your Data/Disclosure of your Data:**

You consent to Our collection, use, disclosure, transfer and storage, of your Data associated with the ARM Community site and you understand and acknowledge that Our Privacy Policy applies to your use of the ARM Community site. 

In registering for an account on the ARM Community site, you will be required to create a user profile. All personal details that you provide for your user profile will be publicly viewable and accessible, however only the mandatory fields need to be completed to create your user profile; any other fields of information can be completed at your discretion. 

We may disclose your Data to third parties in order to assist in providing the site. The Data may be used by us or third parties for the purposes of improving user experience or in assisting with technical support on the ARM Community site. 

We may also use your Data to create user profiles by running a report on professional fields of interests and other Data that is provided as part of your profile. However, we only use this for internal marketing purposes. 

If you have agreed to receive marketing communications from Us, We may use your email address to send you marketing and sales communications, however, We will always provide you with the opportunity to unsubscribe from marketing and sales communications. We may also track your activity on the ARM Community site to send you marketing communication that is of interest to you, but only if you have agreed to receive marketing communications from us. We use cookies on the ARM Community site and you should read ARM’s Cookie Policy to find out further information about how We use cookies. 

If you have registered for a competition on the ARM Community platform We may use your contact details registered on your profile to contact you in respect of the relevant competition. 

If you engage in a conversation on the ARM Community site We may use your Data to respond to you in respect of this conversation or question or if you contribute content which we would like to discuss with you. 

We may integrate the ARM Community site with other ARM Websites in the future and use content you have posted on the ARM Community site on other ARM Websites, We will only link this to your display name when posting this content on other ARM Websites. The type of content that may appear on other ARM Websites is topical conversations in relation to specific products or services at ARM. We will only use this content if the content is posted in an open forum. 

We will endeavour to keep private any conversations you may have on the ARM Community site and only accessible to administrators of the ARM Community site and any parties you make this private conversations public to. 

You may also choose to make your content and Data accessible by other third party sites, We will not be responsible for how this content and Data is used and the third parties privacy policy will apply to this Data and how this data is used. 

Your contact details may also be used if We need to contact you in respect of infringing content you have contributed to the ARM Community site.

We have full discretion to delete your account and any Data and content that you have contritbuted to the ARM Community site at any point and you can request deletion of your account and any Data and content you have contributed to the site. 

During your use of ARM Community site, and during any subsequent changes, updates or attempts to resolve issues you bring to our attention We may access, and collect technical information from or about your use of the services including which devices are used in connection with your use of the ARM Community site. We may use this information for changes to the services or security or maintenance associated with your use of the ARM Community site.

## Disclosure of your Data

**Partners, Subsidiaries and Affiliates.**

Except as expressly stated in this policy or on Our Websites, We do not provide your Data to third parties without your consent. We do share your Data with our parent companies, subsidiaries and ARM’s related companies/ affiliates. Our parent companies, subsidiaries and affiliates will be bound to maintain that Personal Data in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 

**Agents, Consultants and Related Third Parties/ ARM Partners**

We may occasionally share aggregated demographic Data with Our partners/ third party providers. This Data is not linked to any personal information that can identify any individual person.

We process data in the ordinary course of business, including using outside companies to ship orders and if you pay for products by credit card We must provide your name and address to payment processing companies for verification purposes. 

We use third parties to provide services on Our behalf, including running promotions for Us providing catering and technical support. We will provide your relevant Data to them solely for the purposes of the effective delivery of such services. These companies include our marketing agencies, database service providers, backup and disaster recovery service providers, email service providers and others. When we engage another company to perform such functions, we may provide them with information, including Personal Data, in connection with their performance of such functions.

**Other Third Party Connections**

If you connect or integrate any social media services with services we provide, you may receive social notifications either from us or from third party companies providing social media services. You can manage these social notifications through changing your privacy settings on the relevant social media site or discontinuing any interaction with this third party site. If you register and provide information to a forum or blog, the information you provide will be published for anyone to see or where you create a connection between ARM services and third party sites, we may collect, use, disclose, transfer and store/retain information relating to your account with such third party services in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 

**Business Transfer / Sale of Personal Data**

In the event that We sell or buy any business or assets, or if ARM, or substantially all of its assets are acquired by a third party, the relevant Data held by Us will be one of the transferred assets. 

We are not in the business of selling your Personal Data per se. We consider this information to be a vital part of our relationship with you. Therefore, we will not sell your Personal Data to third parties, including third party advertisers. There are, however, certain circumstances in which we may disclose, transfer or share your Data with certain third parties without further notice to you, as set forth in this Privacy Policy.

**Legal Requirement**

We may use / disclose your Data / Personal Data if We are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply Our terms of use and other agreements; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of ARM, Our customers, or others. 

## Your rights

We may, from time to time, send you email or direct mail regarding Our products and services. You have the right to request us to not use your Data for marketing communications. You can ‘opt out’ of receiving electronic communications by clicking on the ‘Unsubscribe’ link at the bottom of any such electronic communication or through following the “opt out” instructions provided in any marketing communications, or by adjusting your subscription settings for your account.

You also have the right to access (review, correct, amend or delete) your Data by contacting Us. You are responsible for providing ARM with accurate and complete personal information, and for contacting Us if correction of such information is required. Please note that, where permitted, We may charge a nominal fee for fulfilling access requests and, to the extent permitted by Law We reserve the right to refuse unreasonable requests for access.

The Data Protection Act 1998 gives you the right to access Personal Data held about you. Your right of access can be exercised in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998. Any access request may be subject to a fee to meet our costs in providing you with details of the Personal Data we hold about you. 

You can browse ARM Websites without providing any Personal Data (other than Data collected in accordance with our Cookie Policy, to the extent that Data is considered Personal Data under applicable laws) or with limiting the Personal Data you provide. If you choose not to provide Personal Data, or limit what Personal Data you provide, you may not be able to use certain functionality or services. 

Please direct any questions concerning ARM's privacy practices or any queries or requests in relation to your Data to privacy@arm.com. 

## Security of your Data

We use industry-standard encryption technologies when transferring and receiving Data. We have appropriate security measures in place to protect against any loss, misuse or alteration of information that We have collected. However, We cannot ensure or otherwise warrant the security of any information you provide to Us or from an ARM Website, and therefore you use the ARM Website at your own risk.

## Retention of your Data

Where you contribute Data via ARM Websites we will generally only keep your Data for as long as is reasonably required for the purpose(s) for which it was submitted. However, on occasion We may retain your Data as long as you continue to use the Services and we may retain your Data for an additional period as is permitted or required under applicable laws. Please note that even if we delete your Data it may persist on backup or archival media for an additional period of time. 

## Changes to this privacy policy

We may revise this privacy policy at any time by amending this page, and where appropriate, by notification on Our Website. You should check this page from time to time to review any changes We have made. Some of the provisions contained in this privacy policy may also be superseded by provisions or notices published elsewhere on Our sites.

Thank you for visiting Our site.

29 November 2016, SP-LES-PRE-20809 Version: 0.6, Copyright (c) 2016 ARM Limited
